Guide to the María Pilar Fort Trigo Diary
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
María Pilar Fort Trigo diary
1936-10-1938-01
MS 2079
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
.42
(1 box)
Diary of María Pilar Fort Trigo, a woman from Valencia, Spain, covering 1936 October through 1938 January, and lacking 1937 December. The diary describes the everyday life of a Spanish woman during the Spanish Civil War and discusses gender relations in Spain and Fort Trigo's engagement to a lawyer, Enrique Jorro Vives. Also includes Fort Trigo's obituary.
Fort Trigo, María Pilar
Biographical / Historical
María Pilar Fort Trigo died on May 27, 2005 in Valencia at the age of 87, widow of Enrique Jorro Vives.
Scope and Contents
Diary of María Pilar Fort Trigo, a woman from Valencia, Spain, covering 1936 October through 1938 January, and lacking 1937 December. The diary describes the everyday life of a Spanish woman during the Spanish Civil War and discusses gender relations in Spain and Fort Trigo's engagement to a lawyer, Enrique Jorro Vives. Also includes Fort Trigo's obituary.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the Librarian for the Latin American and Iberian Collections, 2017. Purchased by the Librarian for the Latin American and Iberian Collections from Kevin Jackson, History Revealed, 2016.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The material is arranged by type of material and therein chronologically.
Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939; Fort Trigo, María Pilar
- October 1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- November 1936 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- December 1936 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- January 1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- February 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- March 1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- April 1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- May 1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- July 1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- August 1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- September 1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- October 1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- November 1937 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- January 1938 (Box 1, Folder 15)